

Frank Hui



About Me

Undergraduate with 8 years of programming experience. I am passionate about technology and hope to use my knowledge for positive impact in the world and the workplace.

Key Skills

Languages Technologies

Git Azure Java Linux Cloud Foundry **Pvthon** Bash Selenium Assembly Twillio JavaScript (JS) Flask C/C++ iQuery REST NodeJS HTML/CSS Bootstrap **AWS** React SQL Google Cloud **Express** R

Education

Simon Fraser University Concurrent Studies, 2019

University of British Columbia Computer Science, Sep. 2020 - Present

Achievements

Top 3 in Canada Halite II, Two Sigma AI Competition 2018

Best Mathematical Science Project Greater Vancouver Regional Science Fair 2018

Best Computer Science Project Greater Vancouver Regional Science Fair 2018,2019

Silver Medal Greater Vancouver Regional Science Fair 2018,2019

Top 20 Award nwHacks 2019

Extracurriculars

Vice President, vhHacks 2019 - 2021 Vancouver's first free high school hackathon

President, VikingsDev 2018 - 2020 Coding club inspiring youth to be programmers

Swimming, travelling, photography, piano, hackathons

Experience

Research Assistant, SFU Computer Science

Sep 2019 - June 2020

- Worked as intern researcher on the project RFDistribution with Dr. Leonid Chindelevitch
- Improved the algorithm for RF distance's running time from $O(1^5)$ to O(I^{3log(I)}) using Number-Theoretic Transform

Private Computer Science Tutor

Sep 2021 - Present

- 50+ hours of tutoring experience, 10+ students per semester
- CPSC 210, 121, 221, 213, MATH 100, 101, 221, EOSC 211 at UBC 90% of students had higher grades after tutoring

joinSDN.com

Jan 2022

- Made a scalable web app for an inclusive gaming community with a NodeJS and Express backend and React frontend
- Deployed on Google Cloud (GCP) using PM2 and a mySQL database to keep track of membership sign up
- Accumulated 65 members in one week

Goblet

Jul 2021

- Lightweight open source video sharing hosting solution using VideoJS, Flask and SocketIO
- Allows users to turn any computer into a video sharing server to watch movies and shows with friends remotely and seamlessly

post_boy Jan 2020

- Official Hack Club shipment tracking app using REST APIs to pull data from Airbase and a Flask backend with Bootstrap and ¡Query frontend
- User authentication done with Slack OAuth 2.0
- Creates transparency for Hack Club, a worldwide organization dedicated to helping growing coding clubs

hs19-flu

Oct 2019

- Trained ML models on phylogenetic data from influenza variants to predict variant success to boost flu vaccine efficacy using R
- Proved that it was possible to use Graph Neural Networks to accomplish this task at hackseq 2019

Apr 2019

- Built a rapid Glioblastoma brain cancer diagnosis tool using three dimensional MRI scan data with an accuracy of 96% using Tensorflow
- Won best Computer Science Project and Silver Medal at GVRSF 2019

Stride

Jan 2019

- Created a mobile Android app that identified people based on their walking patterns with an accuracy of 97% with Tensorflow
- Trained machine learning (ML) models with accelerometer data
- Won Top 20 award at nwHacks 2019

Epidemic Ledger Oct 2018

- Led a team creating a blockchain solution to pandemic tracking
 Project allows epidemiologists identify and treat diseases quickly, while preserving anonymity, security, and correctness
- Used RESTful API to collect data and deployed on AWS